<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Desi Penguin&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://mandarvaze.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Desi Penguin&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mandarvaze.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 Review</title>
      <link>https://mandarvaze.github.io/2020/2019-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mandarvaze.github.io/2020/2019-review/</guid>
      <description>Earlier I wrote about how Jan 1st is not a special date in any way.
While I still believe that for starting something new, or changing, calendar years give us well defined time against which we measure progress (and make plans. Or is it the other way around ?)
365/366 days is well agreed upon time. So it is as good as 30 or 90 days.
While we can &amp;ldquo;start&amp;rdquo; any day and &amp;ldquo;look back&amp;rdquo; approximately 360 days later, we are more likely to do that when everyone considers starting a new year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change What You Don&#39;t Like</title>
      <link>https://mandarvaze.github.io/2020/change-what-you-dont-like/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 13:06:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mandarvaze.github.io/2020/change-what-you-dont-like/</guid>
      <description>These days book I&#39;m reading - Keep Going It has an entire chapter titled
 You are allowed to change your mind&amp;rdquo;
 He talks about how we are &amp;ldquo;afraid&amp;rdquo; to change our mind, as it (now a days) indicates &amp;ldquo;weakness&amp;rdquo;.
Some interesting quotes from this chapter :
 I thought I was wrong about everything. I was wrong about that too.
  If you’ve never changed your mind about something, pinch yourself; you may be dead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year 2020</title>
      <link>https://mandarvaze.github.io/2020/happy-new-year-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 06:09:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mandarvaze.github.io/2020/happy-new-year-2020/</guid>
      <description>Derek Sivers says
 A new year begins when there’s a memorable change in my life. Not January 1st. Nothing changes on January 1st.
 I recently started reading Austin Kleon&#39;s book Keep Going
In it he mentions that making gifts for others gives you joy.
I spent New Year Eve 2019 making these for my kids. (6 and 4 as of this writing) My spouse had to work late (work deadline) and it was just 3 of us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Can Have Peanuts</title>
      <link>https://mandarvaze.github.io/2019/i-can-have-peanuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 07:18:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mandarvaze.github.io/2019/i-can-have-peanuts/</guid>
      <description>I am so grateful that I can have peanuts.
I love peanuts.
Lightly salted.
Lightly roasted without salt.
Cooked (with a little salt)
Or just raw.
Or in Chiwada, or Khichadi
It occurred to me that although it might seem trivial, it is a previledge to be able to eat peanuts.
I know few people - who can not. Because they are old and have &amp;ldquo;teeth problems&amp;rdquo;
Or (as seen on American TV shows) - have peanut allergies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scavengers</title>
      <link>https://mandarvaze.github.io/2018/scavengers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 10:56:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mandarvaze.github.io/2018/scavengers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://source.unsplash.com/OegrZj5C9y0/750x350&#34; alt=&#34;Scavengers&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Actual conversation with my 5 year-old. I was trying to explain about scavengers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Interview</title>
      <link>https://mandarvaze.github.io/2018/tech-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 08:10:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mandarvaze.github.io/2018/tech-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These are actual exchanges from a technical interview I conduced recently. The
person had 2 years experience in an MNC, in what they described as DevOps&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Are a Writer</title>
      <link>https://mandarvaze.github.io/2018/you-are-a-writer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 07:25:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mandarvaze.github.io/2018/you-are-a-writer/</guid>
      <description>You are a writer. (So start acting like one)
I started reading a book by Jeff Goins, with the same name as the title of this post.
In his book, he compares his relationship with writing to his relationship with his girlfriend. How initially everything is exciting, and how later the excitement dies and both people are in a relationship because they &amp;ldquo;can&#39;t get out&amp;rdquo;
He mentions that he &amp;ldquo;divorced&amp;rdquo; his first blog, for the same reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 : Another great year</title>
      <link>https://mandarvaze.github.io/2018/2017-another-great-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 17:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mandarvaze.github.io/2018/2017-another-great-year/</guid>
      <description>Learning Programming Language In the review of 2016, I had written about &amp;ldquo;learning go&amp;rdquo;.
Well, that didn&#39;t happen.
But instead I picked up &amp;ldquo;elixir&amp;rdquo;. I loved it. I did several exercises from codewars.
Initially, the exercises looked too &amp;ldquo;amateurish&amp;rdquo;, but once I hit a road-block, where I was required to use recursion instead of loops, I realized that &amp;ldquo;simple&amp;rdquo; exercises are important to get my head around the functional paradigm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 was a great year</title>
      <link>https://mandarvaze.github.io/2017/2016-was-a-great-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mandarvaze.github.io/2017/2016-was-a-great-year/</guid>
      <description>Some of the highlights of the year gone by
Moved to spacemacs I had started experimenting with spacemacs around late 2015. In 2016, I completely switched to spacemacs. I&#39;m consciously saying spacemacs, because although it is &amp;ldquo;emacs&amp;rdquo; I am used to spacemacs keybindings, and may not be able to use &amp;ldquo;plain&amp;rdquo; emacs on any other system. (Turns out it is said that unlike vi/vim, no two emacs users can use each others system, because of heavy personal customizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 things to make (my) blogging frictionless</title>
      <link>https://mandarvaze.github.io/2016/6-things-to-make-my-blogging-frictionless/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mandarvaze.github.io/2016/6-things-to-make-my-blogging-frictionless/</guid>
      <description>Reflection on some issues I faced. If you find some of these useful, great. The post is not intended as an advice
Background Recently I heard the talk python to me podcast where A. Jesse Davis was interviewed. The topic was a bit different than usual python related topics. It was about how to make blogging easy. Jesse talks about several nice things, including the fact that why we should not feel guilty for not blogging regularly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I moved to Static Blog ?</title>
      <link>https://mandarvaze.github.io/2013/why-i-moved-to-static-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mandarvaze.github.io/2013/why-i-moved-to-static-blog/</guid>
      <description>Little bit of a histoy of my blog at various platforms.
This is my third attempt at blogging.
Wordpress.com First one is still on hosted wordpress site. In a way, that is nice. Pretty much no administration needed. One can install the plugins that are tested by wordpress.com They also upgrade the platform for you. Great for testing the waters for the first time blogger. I think it is better than blogspot (I can&#39;t remember if I had one of those, and moved to wordpress)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>