<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Desi Penguin's Blog</title><link href="http://mandarvaze.github.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://mandarvaze.github.com/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://mandarvaze.github.com/</id><updated>2013-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Installing linux on HP Pavilion m6</title><link href="http://mandarvaze.github.com/2013/02/linux-on-hp-pavilion-m6.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mandar Vaze</name></author><id>tag:mandarvaze.github.com,2013-02-17:2013/02/linux-on-hp-pavilion-m6.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After my trusty? Lenovo Thinkpad R400 developed problems (immediately after the 3 year warranty expired) I had to buy a new laptop. After initially thinking of ultrabook, I finally bought HP Pavilion m6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I needed this laptop for my work, I needed linux on it. I had &lt;em&gt;tried&lt;/em&gt; a live USB on linux mint 13 before I paid for the machine, so I was sure that linux support would not be an issue. Live boot confirmed that display and Wireless worked without problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I decided to make changes, I created the rescue disk (Just to be safe) I ended up needing those not long after :( - By the way, as an aside, it is important to note that rescue disk creator program does &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; accept DVR+RW the ones that can be used to write multiple times. So I had to go back to the shop to get them replaced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main problem is that the machine already has 4 primary partitions. Thus linux installer is unable to create a new partition to boot from.
After looking thru forums, I realized that HP_tools partition can be easily removed. Way to do is :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First assign a drive letter to HP_TOOLS partition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy the files to recovery partition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delete the HP_TOOLS partition -&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recreate if needed, recreated as logical - thus solving max primary partitions problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the max partition problem is resolved, installing linux isn't difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One other thing I did differently was to use Windows boot loader as default instead of GRUB (Felt safe at the time) I used &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://neosmart.net/EasyBCD/"&gt;EasyBCD&lt;/a&gt;
So now I first get Windows bootloader which lets me choose between windows and Linux mint 14 (which is the default) But once I select Linux mint, I get GRUB bootloader (which also consists on Windows 7 entry) So may be I didn't need &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://neosmart.net/EasyBCD/"&gt;EasyBCD&lt;/a&gt; after all. YMMV.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="linux"></category><category term="how-to"></category><category term="hp-m6"></category></entry><entry><title>Review "The Hobbit : An Unexpected Journey"</title><link href="http://mandarvaze.github.com/2012/12/the-hobbit-an-unexpected-journey.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mandar Vaze</name></author><id>tag:mandarvaze.github.com,2012-12-20:2012/12/the-hobbit-an-unexpected-journey.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;img alt="The Hobbit" src="./static/images/hobbit.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I get into my own experience I have some complaints against Peter Jackson and his PR team. Hel,, the &amp;quot;Rise of Guardians&amp;quot; got better publicity (May be due to holiday season and it being kinds movie and/ot due to tie up with McDonald's) &amp;quot;The Hobbit&amp;quot; hardly got any publicity in Pune. If it were not for TV ads, I would not have even known it was released (and I would have mostly missed it) There aren't enough shows in Pune IMO. There were NO ads in the Movie Ads page in DNA.
In addition to all this, Dabbang 2 is releasing next week, taking up all the screens. So my only chance was in the first week. As a LOTR fan, I had to watch it. Unfortunately, there weren't any LOTR fans in my friends/family circle, locally. (Only other LOTR fan I knew was 12 hours away in US) Finally, I watched it before I miss my chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I reached the movie hall, I realized why there wasn't much publicity (or may be it was other way round). There were hardly any people for the show - may be 30 at the max. That means multiplexes were probably running at a loss (Is there such a thing ?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched 3D version - which was most likely HFR version. As others on the interweb have said scenes look surreal. Hence my guess that version I saw was 48FPS one. To explain a little more, it was like looking at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/groups/hdr/"&gt;HDR&lt;/a&gt;  photo. HDR photos look like a great painting. But when you look at a photo, you expect &amp;quot;real like&amp;quot; quality. I had similar feeling when watching The Hobbit. It looks stunning, but you also get the feel that it isn't &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt;. That.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another complaint I have was that due to 3D glasses having a dark shade, the movie looked less bright. I removed my 3D glasses several times, and saw that projection itself was bright enough, but the 3D glasses made it look dark. I heard few other patrons complaining the same. One girl actually said &amp;quot;There is some problem with the glasses they gave me, I'm getting a replacement&amp;quot; (I doubt she did) Since lot of scenes are indoors, in caves and all, there were a LOT of dark (as in less bright) scenes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a feeling, when the movie is available on DVD (or when they air it on TV) - it will be 2D (and possibly 24FPS) and would &lt;strong&gt;look&lt;/strong&gt; much nicer. There are &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.vincentlaforet.com/2012/12/19/the-hobbit-an-unexpected-masterclass-in-why-hfr-fails-and-a-reaffirmation-of-what-makes-cinema-magical/"&gt;others&lt;/a&gt; who preferred 2D version as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that technicalities are out of the way, lets review the movie itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had read the LOTR books first - all three of them, and then watched the movies. Then I &amp;quot;ran into&amp;quot; the Hobbit almost by accident. I was in Bandra on a weekend, and happen to see &amp;quot;The Hobbit&amp;quot; at a roadside used-book store. It was a very tiny book compared to three volumes of LOTR. I probably finished it in a day or two (I was working full time then)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Point of all this is that when Peter Jackson made 3 movies from the 3 LOTR books, he had to cut down a lot of story line. The movies were still very lengthy compared to most English movies. But here he stretched a single book into three movies. The result is that it feels a slow movie. The folks who haven't read the book would be looking at their watch (I just stopped short of doing that myself) As an example, in &amp;quot;The Fellowship&amp;quot; - Tolkien narrates the hobbits' journey out of shire very much in detail. I think the visit to Tom Bombadil alone covered about 100 pages, which was omitted altogether from the movie. But here, Jackson chose to show the initial Dwarf Party at Bilbo's house at length. It doesn't add much value to the movie, IMO. While it has been quite some time since I have read the book, considering that &amp;quot;The Hobbit&amp;quot; was written  before LOTR books, I doubt it originally contained references to the LOTR movie plots like awakening of Sauron - which eats up some time in the movie at Rivendell. Due to these it takes long time till you reach the adventure part of the story. Since I knew the movie didn't contain the entire book, I kept on thinking - &amp;quot;Ok so now the movie will end, rest in next part&amp;quot; at least couple of times, but movie kept on going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the cast - Martin Freeman does a great job as Bilbo. He looks the age too. As per Wikipedia he is 41 in real life but looks much younger in the movie. Not as young as Frodo in LOTR movies, just right. Ian McKellen as already aced the part of Gandalf. Amongst the Dwarves, Richard Armitage is the only one with better role written for him, and does excellent Job of the Prince who has lost his kingdom. For a totally animated character, Gollum was very expressive. His scenes in the cave with Bilbo probably were the highlight of the movie (and the book, as far a I remember)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next time around, for the second part of the trilogy, I plan to watch the movie in a different movie theater - to check whether the 3D glasses impact the brightness everywhere or whether it was problem with this specific movie hall. I would also try to catch 2D version next time, if they release that.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="review"></category><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>My First REAL contribution to open source project</title><link href="http://mandarvaze.github.com/2012/04/my-contribution-to-openstack.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-04-09T21:29:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mandar Vaze</name></author><id>tag:mandarvaze.github.com,2012-04-09:2012/04/my-contribution-to-openstack.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/openstack/melange/commit/d8ff17ecb9466b64dbd064710489ea62843e6636"&gt;fix&lt;/a&gt; for one of the bugs-that-matters in melange subproject of Openstack&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feels good :)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="open source"></category></entry><entry><title>बराह वापरून मराठी blogging</title><link href="http://mandarvaze.github.com/2010/01/braah-vaapruun-mraatthii-blogging.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-17T06:39:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mandar Vaze</name></author><id>tag:mandarvaze.github.com,2010-01-17:2010/01/braah-vaapruun-mraatthii-blogging.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;आत्ताच मी मराठी blogger's मेळाव्याला जाऊन आलो. तिथे मला बराह ह्या software बद्दल समजले.आत्ता मी हे बराहपॅड वापरून लिहीत आहे. सुरवातीला थोडे अवघड वाटले खरे, पण थोड्याच वेळात बऱ्या पैकी जमू लागले आहे.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;जर तुम्हाला मराठी मधे blogging करायचे असेल तर &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.baraha.com/"&gt;barah&lt;/a&gt; नक्की वापरून पहा.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="marathi"></category></entry></feed>