<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Desi Penguin's Blog - thoughts</title><link href="//mandarvaze.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="//mandarvaze.github.io/feeds/thoughts.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>//mandarvaze.github.io/</id><updated>2016-08-23T05:18:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>6 things to make (my) blogging frictionless</title><link href="//mandarvaze.github.io/2016/08/easier-blogging.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-23T05:18:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-23T05:18:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mandar Vaze</name></author><id>tag:mandarvaze.github.io,2016-08-23:/2016/08/easier-blogging.html</id><summary type="html">
&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;
&lt;p class="first admonition-title"&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;These issues apply to &lt;strong&gt;me&lt;/strong&gt;. If you find some of these useful, great.
The post is not intended as an advice to &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="background"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#id1"&gt;Background&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I heard the talk python to me podcast where A. Jesse Davis was
interviewed. The topic was a bit different than usual python related …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;
&lt;p class="first admonition-title"&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;These issues apply to &lt;strong&gt;me&lt;/strong&gt;. If you find some of these useful, great.
The post is not intended as an advice to &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="background"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#id1"&gt;Background&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I heard the talk python to me podcast where A. Jesse Davis was
interviewed. The topic was a bit different than usual python related topics. It
was about how to make blogging easy. Jesse talks about several nice things,
including the fact that why we should &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; feel guilty for not blogging
regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should listen to the podcast
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://talkpython.fm/episodes/show/69/write-an-excellent-programming-blog"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
if you have not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the idea was at the back of my mind for a while, and this post is sort of
brain dump of why I am unable to &lt;strong&gt;publish&lt;/strong&gt; regularly inspite of having content
written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="finalize-the-source-format"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#id2"&gt;Finalize the source format&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kept moving between &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;org&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;rst&lt;/tt&gt;. I liked &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;org&lt;/tt&gt; when I started using
emacs. (In fact that was &lt;strong&gt;the&lt;/strong&gt; reason to start using emacs) So few of my
initial posts are in &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;org&lt;/tt&gt; I had one post in &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;asciidoc&lt;/tt&gt; as well. But I think
I will stick to reStructuredText mainly because most of the static site
generators will have support for this format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even bigger number probably support &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;markdown&lt;/tt&gt; but then there is no
standardization, you have too many flavors out there. Also, I think &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;rst&lt;/tt&gt; is
bit more &lt;em&gt;richer&lt;/em&gt; than &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;markdown&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had one post in &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;asciidoc&lt;/tt&gt; as well&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="create-use-templates"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#id3"&gt;Create/Use templates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to get the thoughts on paper (so to speak) I start typing in an empty
file. By the time I am done, I have very unformatted text that requires
"formatting", and this is where the delay in "publishing" comes in.
I have so many written-but-unpublished posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having templates with headers and categories/tags pre-populated would be good
way to reduce the friction. Jesse talks about how we mostly have about 5
different types of posts. May be create just 5 templates for 5 "types" of blogs,
and remove the decision making from choosing the categories and tags. (I never
remember the list of categories and tags I have used, and always have to search
the older posts to get the list, sorta)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On second thoughts, I think nikola already has a script to create a new posts.
May be I ought to use that ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="write-more-frequently"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#id4"&gt;Write more frequently&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may seem confusing. Let me explain. As I mentioned that I usually start
writing as a plain text, and later "format" the contents. One of reasons why
this happens is because I can't remember the syntax at the time of writing. (and
that happens when one keeps switching between &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;org&lt;/tt&gt; to &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;rst&lt;/tt&gt; to &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;md&lt;/tt&gt;. See
the first point.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I write more often using only one platform, the "formatting" syntax will be
part of my memory. I already write the documentation (using sphinx) in &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;rst&lt;/tt&gt; -
another reason to finalize on &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;rst&lt;/tt&gt; over &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;org&lt;/tt&gt; or &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;md&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="finalize-the-blogging-platform"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#id5"&gt;Finalize the blogging platform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have one blog in pelican. (This one. updated after a long time) and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mandarvaze.bitbucket.io"&gt;other
blog&lt;/a&gt; in nikola. Switching between them just
takes mental effort. If I were to standardize on it, there won't be "switching
trouble"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also want to consider &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;hugo&lt;/tt&gt;, but my initial attempts to get a blog rolling
with a theme-that-i-like hasn't worked well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But irrespective of the blog generator, if I standardize on reStructuredText, I
don't have to worry about switching the blog generators (I think)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="finalize-the-blog-home"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#id6"&gt;Finalize the blog home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a related note, having single home for my blogs also might be good idea. It
is always an effort to decide where should a specific post go. While with my
second blog, the idea is very clear - it is about "what I learnt", so things
like "thoughts" should not go there. Yet, sometimes it is not easy. May be just
have one blog with category as "wiltw" (short for "What I learnt this week")&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="focus-on-the-content"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#id7"&gt;Focus on the content&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am never happy with the themes. I was almost happy with Material Design theme
for nikola, but it could not render bullets (can you imagine?) So I switched to
a simpler theme. But I am not happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I should just pick one up, stick with it, and not worry about the "look"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have read several great blogs that look down right ugly, but the contents are
worth in gold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="publish-now-refine-later"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#id8"&gt;Publish now, refine later&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perfectionist in me wants to read-edit-read a LOT after my initial writing is
done. I spend a lot of time in this. May be I should just publish it first, and
then refine it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="blogging"></category></entry><entry><title>Moving to Macbook</title><link href="//mandarvaze.github.io/2015/05/move-to-macbook.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mandar Vaze</name></author><id>tag:mandarvaze.github.io,2015-05-12:/2015/05/move-to-macbook.html</id><summary type="html">
&lt;div class="section" id="background"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#id1"&gt;Background&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been meaning to buy a Macbook for quite some time. No doubt, they are way
above the average. The very first one I saw (in hand) years ago, was Macbook
air. It was so thin (and there was so much press coverage) I adored the thinness
and …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;div class="section" id="background"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#id1"&gt;Background&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been meaning to buy a Macbook for quite some time. No doubt, they are way
above the average. The very first one I saw (in hand) years ago, was Macbook
air. It was so thin (and there was so much press coverage) I adored the thinness
and left it at that. There was anti-osx/apple "majority" in that startup, all
the developers used Linux, and the "boss" had iPad, and Macbook air. So it was
considered "business" machine (The cost also kinda justified that only the
executives could afford it)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, I started noticing more macs in the developer community. Couple
years ago, I attended an Advanced Python course. The instructor was using Mac,
not only that, one of the student was also using mac. Since we spent 3 days
together, I asked him a lot of questions about mac. Still nothing for another
year. Then one of the person I worked with (Earlier) bought Macbook air (used)
He used to be a die-hard ubuntu user. Things were changing. (When I met him
recently, turns out he installed Ubuntu on the Macbook air. People don't change
who they are.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then recently, one of my junior colleague bought Macbook pro. That probably was
the last straw on the camel's back. I couldn't/shouldn't say any more that it is
costly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="why-mac-my-reasons"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#id2"&gt;Why Mac (my reasons)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always wanted a laptop that was light and had great battery life. Macbook is
that, always. I didn't care so much for OS X. But I also knew that I could get
the great battery life only with OS X. (I checked with the person who installed
ubuntu on his Macbook air. Turns out he didn't get as great battery life, but
_he_ didn't care. He still has very light weight Ubuntu laptop, with better
screen)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I honestly and seriously looked at the "PC" alternatives. None came even closer
to the specs. When they did, they were costlier than Macbook Pro. In that sense,
Macs are not "expensive". Also, most high-end "PC" laptops these days seem to
come with touchscreen. That, I don't like. In that sense, I think Apple
understands that touchscreen market is iPad, and laptop is a totally different
market. So they kept them separate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="choosing-the-model"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#id3"&gt;Choosing the model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you look on the net for the comparison with the air, you'll see that pro and
air are very close. For slightly(?) higher cost, pro is a better machine, for a
developer anyway. Also, if you buy in India, air comes only with 4GB RAM, while
pro comes with 8GB. Considering that macs can't be hardware upgraded, maxing out
the specs in the available budget is the only option. I thought 128GB SSD (Entry
level option) may be turn out to be restrictive, if I decide to dual-boot. So I
went with 256GB (512GB would have been even better, but the cost goes up)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15" has better specs (16GB default RAM) but it is heavy (and cost goes up)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-wait"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#id4"&gt;The Wait&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had been "thinking" for almost 4 months. I asked my mac user friends for some
advice(Should I go for "older" model to save the money. They suggested to go
with the latest model) Yet I was not able to make up my mind whether I "need"
the mac. WAF (Wife Acceptance Factor) was also a concern, buy she easily agreed.
(I didn't wait to check "why" she agreed so easily, lest she changed her mind)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, decided to take the plunge (It really was that) Normally people order
online, and "wait" for few days. But I was lucky. I purchased from someone who
supplied hardware at my wife's office. I did the payment around noon, and by
2PM, I had the laptop in my hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in case you order online, there is a great discussion on quora on what to do
while waiting for your mac to arrive. I had done that and more research while I
was still making up my mind. e.g. Turns out OS X file system is case-insensitive
(but case preserving) Having used Linux (and *nix) for over 2 decades, my
instincts were to convert the file system to case-sensitive (There is an option
to do that) But after enough warnings, I decided not to. (I know I am never
going to install Adobe products that won't install on case-sensitive file
system, or install "Steam", yet being new to OS X, I want to respect their
choice.) I had also known about iTerm2, Adium, homebrew and the likes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="first-impressions"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#id5"&gt;First Impressions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The screen is gorgeous. It is one thing to read about it, but to experience it,
is a completely different matter. Everything just looks better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trackpad is awesome. multi-touch gestures are natural. e.g. To see the
notification panel on the right, feels as if, you are using the touch screen to
"bring it in", except via the Trackpad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of the box, battery remaining was shown as 12+ hours - Amazing. It is
unclear how the remaining battery life is calculated, because it keeps going up
and down. "Apps using significant energy" is a nice touch, Turns out Google
Chrome sucks battery, but over a period I realized that Firefox isn't any
better, neither is safari. I don't have the numbers, this is based on what is
reported as "Apps using significant energy".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="teething-problems"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#id6"&gt;(Teething) Problems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the First bootup, there is a step to automatically set the timezone based
on the location. But that did not work, so I had to set it up manually. No big
deal but ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After selecting the timezone, I had to set the city. I was amazed to see that
Pune or Mumbai were not listed, but smaller cities like solapur, nanded, nagpur
were. I had to type in, then Found Pune. Not sure how the initial city list is
populated. Again, No big deal but ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having never used OSX, I didn't know "How to get started", was looking for
"Tour". Didn't find anything obvious. Was under "Finder -&amp;gt; help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macbok Pro Essentials "Free" book was suggested, at the end of the "Get to know
your Mac" It kept on downloading - but never could open it. So I asked for help
on the apple forum. Problem solved :
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://discussions.apple.com/thread/7021641"&gt;https://discussions.apple.com/thread/7021641&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="concluding-thoughts"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#id7"&gt;Concluding thoughts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the move was worth it. Now there is no "going back". I know why people
love Mac from "this" side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a software developer, and can afford it, you should &lt;strong&gt;definitely&lt;/strong&gt;
"switch"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; you can't afford it, think again ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can't afford &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt;, start saving ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="thoughts"></category><category term="osx"></category></entry><entry><title>I do not have a task</title><link href="//mandarvaze.github.io/2014/03/i-do-not-have-a-task.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mandar Vaze</name></author><id>tag:mandarvaze.github.io,2014-03-23:/2014/03/i-do-not-have-a-task.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Showing initiative to help yourself&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start ups are considered (by some) as best opportunity to advance one’s career. Irrespective of your years of experience or previous background, start ups will let you work on variety of tasks without specifying boundary.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is sad when a start up employee says …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Showing initiative to help yourself&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start ups are considered (by some) as best opportunity to advance one’s career. Irrespective of your years of experience or previous background, start ups will let you work on variety of tasks without specifying boundary.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is sad when a start up employee says or thinks “I am done working on what I was asked, and have no next task”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless it is your first day/week, you probably know the pulse of the organization. You also (should) know various projects/products/initiatives being perused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start ups are always short of resources. There is always more work than people available. Show initiative, that is the only way to grow. If you keep expecting “work to be assigned” to you, you are probably not a good fit for a start up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the various things one can do when waiting for formally being assigned the next task ?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look at the bug tracking system :  see which bugs/features you can address and volunteer for those. Even if you do not end up working on it, at least you would have now understood — probably unknown till now — part of the code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn new technology : This might be more time consuming, but you should be doing this anyway, probably along with your main assignment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make performance improvements : Depending on the time you have till the next assignment, this may or may not be possible. But you can get started ☺&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review code written by  peers. This helps you learn to write better code, also helps you reduce code review comments if any, especially if you are a junior associate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check to see if you can help with non-development related work, and expand your mind by knowing other parts of business. This could be looking at front end code, if you are a back end developer, or vice versa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can also try to get involved in non-technical work. Create an internal company newsletter. Try out new tools company can use for collaboration. Update the documentation. Write up suggested updates for the company website and send suggestions to the founders. If the company facebook/twitter account is non-functional or not well utilized, volunteer to run that. (Thanks  Navin Kabra , for suggesting this entire bullet)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to learn more about the domain you are working on. This might help you understand implicit requirements in your field of work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not restricted to start ups, People should be doing this in any organization, and there are lots of big companies where this is encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I assumed more “established” companies may have problems when junior person “tries to look around”, on the other hand start ups may welcome it. I’m sure there are exception in either cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thanks to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://medium.com/&amp;#64;ngkabra"&gt;Navin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://medium.com/&amp;#64;iamSB"&gt;Sushrut&lt;/a&gt; for Reviewing the draft and making this post better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Originally posted on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://medium.com/p/51cfa20c5e1e"&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content><category term="thoughts"></category><category term="advice"></category><category term="startup"></category></entry><entry><title>Information at the fingertips is overrated</title><link href="//mandarvaze.github.io/2014/02/info-fingertips-overrated.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mandar Vaze</name></author><id>tag:mandarvaze.github.io,2014-02-07:/2014/02/info-fingertips-overrated.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It does not solve world hunger&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do I think it is overrated ? It is because human beings are lazy by nature. I can probably cite biological reasons like caveman had to conserve energy, do not waste energy on things that can be avoided. But that was probably true in …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It does not solve world hunger&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do I think it is overrated ? It is because human beings are lazy by nature. I can probably cite biological reasons like caveman had to conserve energy, do not waste energy on things that can be avoided. But that was probably true in case of physicial work, but guess these lazy genes take over even in the information age... and I think our genes may not be wrong. Just look at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.google.co.in/search?q=thinking+burns+more+calories"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it is fair to assume that lack of information definitely &lt;em&gt;blocks&lt;/em&gt;, but having the information isn't the silver bullet either.
I am not talking about the information overload either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the examples of why I think it is overrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I shared password for demo site w/ my boss multiple times via email - Even then, just before the demo he needs to ask the login credentials to me. It was always in his mailbox - but it is easier to ask.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I spent a lot of time to write detailed root cause of a problem via email with my team mates. Still we have to have a meeting and discuss (and waste X hours multipled by Y developers ? when reading individually and spending time thinking and efforts to understand by oneself would have been more effective IMO)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;dl class="first docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;In the product I created :&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul class="first last"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customers have their &amp;quot;TO DO&amp;quot; list shown to them when they login, still they need email reminder before the task is due. So we send reminder 15 and 5 days before the task is due. Now their &amp;quot;managers&amp;quot; need email reminder 2 days before the task is due.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is online report for customers, still they expect the reports to be emailed to them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all the cases - the lack of information was never a problem, neither was information overload (may be only in case where password was needed to be searched from lot of emails)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was originally published on my other blog&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog-desipenguin.rhcloud.com/information-at-the-fingertips-is-overrated/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="thoughts"></category></entry><entry><title>Why I moved to Static Blog ?</title><link href="//mandarvaze.github.io/2013/04/why-move-to-static-blog.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mandar Vaze</name></author><id>tag:mandarvaze.github.io,2013-04-18:/2013/04/why-move-to-static-blog.html</id><summary type="html">
&lt;!-- 1  Wordpress.com
2  Self-hosted Wordpress
3  Posterous
4  Finally, Static website ...
5  Securing the source --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my third attempt at blogging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="wordpress-com"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#id1"&gt;Wordpress.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mandarvaze.wordpress.com"&gt;First&lt;/a&gt; one is still on hosted wordpress site.
In a way, that is nice. Pretty much no administration needed.
One can install the plugins that are tested by wordpress.com They also upgrade
the platform for you. Great for testing the …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;!-- 1  Wordpress.com
2  Self-hosted Wordpress
3  Posterous
4  Finally, Static website ...
5  Securing the source --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my third attempt at blogging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="wordpress-com"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#id1"&gt;Wordpress.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mandarvaze.wordpress.com"&gt;First&lt;/a&gt; one is still on hosted wordpress site.
In a way, that is nice. Pretty much no administration needed.
One can install the plugins that are tested by wordpress.com They also upgrade
the platform for you. Great for testing the waters for the first time blogger.
I think it is better than blogspot (&lt;em&gt;I can't remember if I had one of those, and moved to wordpress&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="self-hosted-wordpress"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#id2"&gt;Self-hosted Wordpress&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But after a while one (&lt;em&gt;at least, I&lt;/em&gt;) becomes ambitious. I had my own wordpress blog hosted on my own domain.
It was a great experience. I got to try my hands at setting my blog &lt;em&gt;just the way I want&lt;/em&gt;.
But after initial excitement was over, it started to become burden. One had to
spend a lot more time administering the blog (upgrade to latest version of wordpress, and the plugins) and less focus on writing.
I never upgrade the blog to wordpress 3 (&lt;em&gt;which by now is very mature&lt;/em&gt;)
I always kept postponing it because upgrade might &lt;em&gt;break&lt;/em&gt; things,
so I would do it when I have enough time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, after a while I wasn't writing much, and stopped paying
attention to the blog. I had also used my &lt;em&gt;non-standard&lt;/em&gt; email ID with
the hosting provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cascading effect was recently I lost access to my blog and the domain.
It was completely my fault. My hosting provider did send multiple reminders
for renewal, but I wasn't checking that account often enough, and when I finally
did, they had probably given up. (&lt;em&gt;I did contact them later, but they ignored my emails&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I definitely learnt a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="posterous"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#id3"&gt;Posterous&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then while I still had my self-hosted wordpress blog, along came posterous.
What I liked about them was I could post via email. I really liked the concept.
They didn't great themes like wordpress, but if the focus was writing, then it
shouldn't matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.... and then they were acquired by twitter. As everyone had predicted, twitter shut them down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was kinda the last straw. I had two blows back to back (One was my own fault, other not so much)
But the result was in both cases, I had lost access to my blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="finally-static-website"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#id4"&gt;Finally, Static website ...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the time, static website generators were picking up.
Over at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://news.ycombinator.com/"&gt;HN&lt;/a&gt; I came across several options like &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://octopress.org/"&gt;Octopress&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll"&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/getpelican"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; .
(&lt;em&gt;I chose Pelican because it is written in Python, language which I am comfortable with, as opposed to Jekyll and Octopress.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is easy to host the static website anywhere, include the Free Heroku plan (Which I might do in future)
But hosting it on github seemed like an easy and popular choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BTW, I did get a backup of all my posterous posts, but they were in XML format. Format which was not useful to me as-it-is.
There is a ruby script that "downloads" all your posterous posts and converts them to markdown. It was not without problems, but it worked. But it is a topic for another post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="securing-the-source"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#id5"&gt;Securing the source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on my recent experience, I am aware that github might one fine day decide to stop supporting this feature.
But if they did, that is OK too, because I will still have access to my contents in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/mandarvaze/mandarvaze-blog-src"&gt;git repo&lt;/a&gt; in the form of "source code"
With Pelican I can re-generate the pages, and host it someplace else (like Heroku)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if github shuts down (or makes all accounts paid, or bought over my big company, and the parent company shuts it down, whatever..)
I have already thought of contingency plan for that as well. I push the same "code" to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bitbucket.org/mandarvaze/mandarvaze-blog-src"&gt;bitbucket repo&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I think chances of both github &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; bitbucket going away at the same time are slim to none,
One can always have the copy of local git repo in the dropbox folder, for additional security, Can you not ? :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="thoughts"></category><category term="musings"></category></entry></feed>