<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Desi Penguin's Blog</title><link href="http://mandarvaze.github.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://mandarvaze.github.com/feeds/thoughts.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://mandarvaze.github.com/</id><updated>2014-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>I do not have a task</title><link href="http://mandarvaze.github.com/2014/03/i-do-not-have-a-task.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mandar Vaze</name></author><id>tag:mandarvaze.github.com,2014-03-23:2014/03/i-do-not-have-a-task.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Showing initiative to help yourself&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start ups are considered (by some) as best opportunity to advance one’s career. Irrespective of your years of experience or previous background, start ups will let you work on variety of tasks without specifying boundary.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is sad when a start up employee says or thinks “I am done working on what I was asked, and have no next task”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless it is your first day/week, you probably know the pulse of the organization. You also (should) know various projects/products/initiatives being perused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start ups are always short of resources. There is always more work than people available. Show initiative, that is the only way to grow. If you keep expecting “work to be assigned” to you, you are probably not a good fit for a start up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the various things one can do when waiting for formally being assigned the next task ?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look at the bug tracking system :  see which bugs/features you can address and volunteer for those. Even if you do not end up working on it, at least you would have now understood — probably unknown till now — part of the code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn new technology : This might be more time consuming, but you should be doing this anyway, probably along with your main assignment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make performance improvements : Depending on the time you have till the next assignment, this may or may not be possible. But you can get started ☺&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review code written by  peers. This helps you learn to write better code, also helps you reduce code review comments if any, especially if you are a junior associate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check to see if you can help with non-development related work, and expand your mind by knowing other parts of business. This could be looking at front end code, if you are a back end developer, or vice versa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can also try to get involved in non-technical work. Create an internal company newsletter. Try out new tools company can use for collaboration. Update the documentation. Write up suggested updates for the company website and send suggestions to the founders. If the company facebook/twitter account is non-functional or not well utilized, volunteer to run that. (Thanks  Navin Kabra , for suggesting this entire bullet)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to learn more about the domain you are working on. This might help you understand implicit requirements in your field of work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not restricted to start ups, People should be doing this in any organization, and there are lots of big companies where this is encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I assumed more “established” companies may have problems when junior person “tries to look around”, on the other hand start ups may welcome it. I’m sure there are exception in either cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thanks to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://medium.com/&amp;#64;ngkabra"&gt;Navin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://medium.com/&amp;#64;iamSB"&gt;Sushrut&lt;/a&gt; for Reviewing the draft and making this post better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Originally posted on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://medium.com/p/51cfa20c5e1e"&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="thoughts"></category><category term="advice"></category><category term="startup"></category></entry><entry><title>Information at the fingertips is overrated</title><link href="http://mandarvaze.github.com/2014/02/info-fingertips-overrated.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mandar Vaze</name></author><id>tag:mandarvaze.github.com,2014-02-07:2014/02/info-fingertips-overrated.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It does not solve world hunger&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do I think it is overrated ? It is because human beings are lazy by nature. I can probably cite biological reasons like caveman had to conserve energy, do not waste energy on things that can be avoided. But that was probably true in case of physicial work, but guess these lazy genes take over even in the information age... and I think our genes may not be wrong. Just look at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.google.co.in/search?q=thinking+burns+more+calories"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it is fair to assume that lack of information definitely &lt;em&gt;blocks&lt;/em&gt;, but having the information isn't the silver bullet either.
I am not talking about the information overload either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the examples of why I think it is overrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;I shared password for demo site w/ my boss multiple times via email - Even then, just before the demo he needs to ask the login credentials to me. It was always in his mailbox - but it is easier to ask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;I spent a lot of time to write detailed root cause of a problem via email with my team mates. Still we have to have a meeting and discuss (and waste X hours multipled by Y developers ? when reading individually and spending time thinking and efforts to understand by oneself would have been more effective IMO)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;dl class="first docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;In the product I created :&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul class="first last simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customers have their &amp;quot;TO DO&amp;quot; list shown to them when they login, still they need email reminder before the task is due. So we send reminder 15 and 5 days before the task is due. Now their &amp;quot;managers&amp;quot; need email reminder 2 days before the task is due.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is online report for customers, still they expect the reports to be emailed to them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all the cases - the lack of information was never a problem, neither was information overload (may be only in case where password was needed to be searched from lot of emails)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was originally published on my other blog&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog-desipenguin.rhcloud.com/information-at-the-fingertips-is-overrated/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="thoughts"></category></entry><entry><title>Why I moved to Static Blog ?</title><link href="http://mandarvaze.github.com/2013/04/why-move-to-static-blog.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mandar Vaze</name></author><id>tag:mandarvaze.github.com,2013-04-18:2013/04/why-move-to-static-blog.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is my third attempt at blogging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="wordpress-com"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wordpress.com&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mandarvaze.wordpress.com"&gt;First&lt;/a&gt; one is still on hosted wordpress site.
In a way, that is nice. Pretty much no administration needed.
One can install the plugins that are tested by wordpress.com They also upgrade
the platform for you. Great for testing the waters for the first time blogger.
I think it is better than blogspot (&lt;em&gt;I can't remember if I had one of those, and moved to wordpress&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="self-hosted-wordpress"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Self-hosted Wordpress&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But after a while one (&lt;em&gt;at least, I&lt;/em&gt;) becomes ambitious. I had my own wordpress blog hosted on my own domain.
It was a great experience. I got to try my hands at setting my blog &lt;em&gt;just the way I want&lt;/em&gt;.
But after initial excitement was over, it started to become burden. One had to
spend a lot more time administering the blog (upgrade to latest version of wordpress, and the plugins) and less focus on writing.
I never upgrade the blog to wordpress 3 (&lt;em&gt;which by now is very mature&lt;/em&gt;)
I always kept postponing it because upgrade might &lt;em&gt;break&lt;/em&gt; things,
so I would do it when I have enough time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, after a while I wasn't writing much, and stopped paying
attention to the blog. I had also used my &lt;em&gt;non-standard&lt;/em&gt; email ID with
the hosting provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cascading effect was recently I lost access to my blog and the domain.
It was completely my fault. My hosting provider did send multiple reminders
for renewal, but I wasn't checking that account often enough, and when I finally
did, they had probably given up. (&lt;em&gt;I did contact them later, but they ignored my emails&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I definitely learnt a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="posterous"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Posterous&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then while I still had my self-hosted wordpress blog, along came posterous.
What I liked about them was I could post via email. I really liked the concept.
They didn't great themes like wordpress, but if the focus was writing, then it
shouldn't matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.... and then they were acquired by twitter. As everyone had predicted, twitter shut them down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was kinda the last straw. I had two blows back to back (One was my own fault, other not so much)
But the result was in both cases, I had lost access to my blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="finally-static-website"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Finally, Static website ...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the time, static website generators were picking up.
Over at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://news.ycombinator.com/"&gt;HN&lt;/a&gt; I came across several options like &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://octopress.org/"&gt;Octopress&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll"&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/getpelican"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; .
(&lt;em&gt;I chose Pelican because it is written in Python, language which I am comfortable with, as opposed to Jekyll and Octopress.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is easy to host the static website anywhere, include the Free Heroku plan (Which I might do in future)
But hosting it on github seemed like an easy and popular choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BTW, I did get a backup of all my posterous posts, but they were in XML format. Format which was not useful to me as-it-is.
There is a ruby script that &amp;quot;downloads&amp;quot; all your posterous posts and converts them to markdown. It was not without problems, but it worked. But it is a topic for another post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="securing-the-source"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Securing the source&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on my recent experience, I am aware that github might one fine day decide to stop supporting this feature.
But if they did, that is OK too, because I will still have access to my contents in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/mandarvaze/mandarvaze-blog-src"&gt;git repo&lt;/a&gt; in the form of &amp;quot;source code&amp;quot;
With Pelican I can re-generate the pages, and host it someplace else (like Heroku)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if github shuts down (or makes all accounts paid, or bought over my big company, and the parent company shuts it down, whatever..)
I have already thought of contingency plan for that as well. I push the same &amp;quot;code&amp;quot; to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bitbucket.org/mandarvaze/mandarvaze-blog-src"&gt;bitbucket repo&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I think chances of both github &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; bitbucket going away at the same time are slim to none,
One can always have the copy of local git repo in the dropbox folder, for additional security, Can you not ? :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="thoughts"></category><category term="musings"></category></entry></feed>