<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Desi Penguin's Blog</title><link href="http://mandarvaze.github.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://mandarvaze.github.com/feeds/tutorial.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://mandarvaze.github.com/</id><updated>2013-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Ghost on Openshift</title><link href="http://mandarvaze.github.com/2013/12/ghost-on-openshift.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mandar Vaze</name></author><id>tag:mandarvaze.github.com,2013-12-31:2013/12/ghost-on-openshift.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Installing Ghost wasn't difficult at all, especially with all the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.openshift.com/quickstarts/ghost-on-openshift"&gt;great documentation&lt;/a&gt; supplied by Openshift community&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="email-setup"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Email Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as I did initial deployment, I got a notification that I need to fix the email configuration. I went with default setup using the Mailgun setup recommended by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://docs.ghost.org/mail/"&gt;the documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="theme-setup"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Theme Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next thing was to change the default casper theme. This turned surprisingly difficult (here is where intuition that one builds due to the experience comes in handy .. more on that a little later)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As listed on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://docs.ghost.org/themes/"&gt;ghost documentation&lt;/a&gt; I went to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://marketplace.ghost.org/"&gt;marketplace gallary&lt;/a&gt; and liked Vapor and Ghostium themes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I assumed (not completely incorrect though) that I need to clone the theme projects into ../content/themes folder, along side the casper folder that came by default. I did the same for both the themes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next thing was to &amp;quot;apply&amp;quot; these to my installation. After having these two theme folders, I thought all I needed was to restart the application using&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;rhc app-restart appname
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I went the settings page, but no new themes .. Hmm ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I quickly realized that the way openshift deployments work (not unlike heroku, which I haven't used) is by pushing any changes to the git repo. So added both the theme folders to git (along with previous changes for the mail setup I did earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Restarted the app&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK, now two new themes appeared in the drop down.
Selected one, clicked &amp;quot;Save&amp;quot;, went on to the main page, and ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Failed to lookup view &amp;quot;index&amp;quot;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK, so this theme may be bad, let me try another one. Same error. What could be wrong ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google search revealed that this errors shows up when index.hbs and post.hbs files are missing (They were not for either of the themes)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, I could go back to default casper theme. (But then I didn't like it so much, that is why I needed a different theme)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I tried another theme from the forums. This one was available only as a zip file.. and guess what - this worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmm ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the theme I chose was a &amp;quot;Featured&amp;quot; theme, so it can't have wrong code ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I downloaded the ZIP file of the same repo from the github (contents would be same, except I won't be able to update the theme easily)
As suggested somewhere - I had also checked the file permissions (all were 644/rw-r--r--) same as in the ZIP file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="intuition-helps"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Intuition helps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure what made me use the ZIP files (from github) in place of the cloned repo. The previous theme that worked may have something to do with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it is intuition from troubleshooting various problems over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it worked. I got the zip file, and placed it at the same place, git commit/push/restart later, I was successfully able to apply the new theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still not sure what is the difference, may be I'll troubleshoot more, but that would be the topic for another post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2013 ended with a Bang !!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2014 will be equally fulfilling and challenging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was originally published on the newly deployed ghost blog on openshift - Duh !! The reason to reproduce it here is because I haven't (yet) spent time to figure out if and how I can backup my posts. I've been bitten twice, so I am being careful. Plus this will remain my primary blog anyway, although publishing on Ghost was a pleasure, more on that later, in another post perhaps.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Since I used reStructuredText format instead of markdown for this blog, it took a little more effort than I had expected&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="troubleshooting"></category><category term="blogging"></category><category term="ghost"></category><category term="openshift"></category></entry><entry><title>How to convert posterous blog to Markdown</title><link href="http://mandarvaze.github.com/2013/04/posterous-to-markdown.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mandar Vaze</name></author><id>tag:mandarvaze.github.com,2013-04-23:2013/04/posterous-to-markdown.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I have written in a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mandarvaze.github.io/2013/04/why-move-to-static-blog.html"&gt;previous&lt;/a&gt; post, I recently consolidated all of various blogs into this one.
Big one was posterous, especially because it is going away in a few days time, and I had two separate blogs (spaces as they used to call it) with them.
While the other posts talked about &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; this one talks about &lt;em&gt;How&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="option-1"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Option 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Posterous provides a backup of all your articles, in XML format. while initially I thought this format may not be useful for importing into pelican, looking back, it might be. I haven't tried it, so I don't know whether it helps. For more details  refer to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://docs.getpelican.com/en/3.1.1/importer.html"&gt;pelican documentation&lt;/a&gt;
Hopefully this is easier of the two routes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="option-2"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Option 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First you need to &amp;quot;get&amp;quot; your postreous posts from their server to your local machine.
You can use this &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/bmann/posterous-export/blob/master/posterous-export.rb"&gt;original&lt;/a&gt; script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to make some &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/mandarvaze/posterous-export/blob/master/posterous-export.rb"&gt;changes&lt;/a&gt; to the script, to make it work for me. I suggest you keep both of them handy.
&lt;em&gt;I am not a ruby developer. so my changes are rudimentary, not the way ruby developer would do. But based on the logic, some old style debugging, and stackover help for ruby syntax, I was able to get it to work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="fun-begins"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fun Begins&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the script to work, you need (ruby off course) posterous &amp;quot;gem&amp;quot;. Consider this as a library or a package, if you aren't familair with Ruby.
not being a ruby programmer, I didn't know this, so I got the following error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;sudo gem install posterous
&lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;sudo&lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; password &lt;span class="k"&gt;for &lt;/span&gt;mandar:
Fetching: ffi-1.7.0.gem &lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;100%&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
Building native extensions.  This could take a &lt;span class="k"&gt;while&lt;/span&gt;...
ERROR:  Error installing posterous:
    ERROR: Failed to build gem native extension.

    /usr/bin/ruby1.9.1 extconf.rb
 /usr/lib/ruby/1.9.1/rubygems/custom_require.rb:36:in &lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;require&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;: cannot load such file -- mkmf (LoadError)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;     from /usr/lib/ruby/1.9.1/rubygems/custom_require.rb:36:in `require&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
     from extconf.rb:4:in &lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt;main&amp;gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;

 Gem files will remain installed in /var/lib/gems/1.9.1/gems/ffi-1.7.0 &lt;span class="k"&gt;for &lt;/span&gt;inspection.
 Results logged to /var/lib/gems/1.9.1/gems/ffi-1.7.0/ext/ffi_c/gem_make.out
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some googline revealed that this is a know problem which can be fixed by&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;sudo apt-get install ruby1.9.1-dev
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I was successfully able to install the posterous gem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="modifying-posterous-gem"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Modifying posterous gem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Original error went away, the script moved forward till the next error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;The option: username is invalid. &lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Ethon::Errors::InvalidOption&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
Please try userpwd instead of username.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Found the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/posterous/posterous-gem/issues/5#issuecomment-13539354"&gt;workaround&lt;/a&gt; on github posterous gem issues list&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that initial problem went away, I started getting the problems in the script itself. Good thing was I learnt &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/3955688/how-do-i-debug-ruby-scripts"&gt;debugging&lt;/a&gt; ruby script via printf method.
Realized there was problem w/ save_media. So at first I commented this function call, and then eveything was OK. I successfuly downloaded all my posts from one of the blogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="getting-the-images"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting the images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I was partially successful, I wanted to make sure I get the images as well. So I added further debug/printf like statements, and in the process learnt about &amp;quot;if my_object.nil? &amp;quot; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lukaszwrobel.pl/blog/ruby-is-nil"&gt;idiom&lt;/a&gt;
With that I was able to get the images as well from my second blog. (and then another pass at my first blog, with images)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="this-is-just-the-beginning"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;This is just the beginning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you have your posts from posterous secured, the &amp;quot;deadline&amp;quot; pressure of posterous going away on April 30th, 2013 is removed. But I coulnd't just use the converted files as is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markdown files didn't work with pelican directly, even after installing Markdown python module in my virtual environment. I ran into &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://martinbrochhaus.com/2012/02/pelican.html#comment-726961261"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; error. (&lt;em&gt;BTW, you should totally boormark the article on which the comment is made&lt;/em&gt;) So I &lt;em&gt;hand converted&lt;/em&gt; the md files to rst. It didn't take that long, but was a manual process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Links from posterous don't work, especially for images that were uploaded to posterous. These links point to posterous' own Amazon S3 (which will also go away soon) But you have the images downloaded by the ruby script, so all the links need to be fixed (manually)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also did some editing. Not all my posts were moved. e.g. One of my posts &amp;quot;Why posterous rocks&amp;quot; didn't make it to this blog :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still learning the rst and pelican, so reference to local images folder works &amp;quot;partially&amp;quot; Luckily, most other places, I was already referring to third party image URL, so it didn't matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="how-to"></category><category term="ruby"></category><category term="learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Installing linux on HP Pavilion m6</title><link href="http://mandarvaze.github.com/2013/02/linux-on-hp-pavilion-m6.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mandar Vaze</name></author><id>tag:mandarvaze.github.com,2013-02-17:2013/02/linux-on-hp-pavilion-m6.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After my trusty? Lenovo Thinkpad R400 developed problems (immediately after the 3 year warranty expired) I had to buy a new laptop. After initially thinking of ultrabook, I finally bought HP Pavilion m6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I needed this laptop for my work, I needed linux on it. I had &lt;em&gt;tried&lt;/em&gt; a live USB on linux mint 13 before I paid for the machine, so I was sure that linux support would not be an issue. Live boot confirmed that display and Wireless worked without problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I decided to make changes, I created the rescue disk (Just to be safe) I ended up needing those not long after :( - By the way, as an aside, it is important to note that rescue disk creator program does &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; accept DVR+RW the ones that can be used to write multiple times. So I had to go back to the shop to get them replaced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main problem is that the machine already has 4 primary partitions. Thus linux installer is unable to create a new partition to boot from.
After looking thru forums, I realized that HP_tools partition can be easily removed. Way to do is :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First assign a drive letter to HP_TOOLS partition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy the files to recovery partition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delete the HP_TOOLS partition -&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recreate if needed, recreated as logical - thus solving max primary partitions problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the max partition problem is resolved, installing linux isn't difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One other thing I did differently was to use Windows boot loader as default instead of GRUB (Felt safe at the time) I used &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://neosmart.net/EasyBCD/"&gt;EasyBCD&lt;/a&gt;
So now I first get Windows bootloader which lets me choose between windows and Linux mint 14 (which is the default) But once I select Linux mint, I get GRUB bootloader (which also consists on Windows 7 entry) So may be I didn't need &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://neosmart.net/EasyBCD/"&gt;EasyBCD&lt;/a&gt; after all. YMMV.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="linux"></category><category term="how-to"></category><category term="hp-m6"></category></entry></feed>